<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="almanac_story">What if every story you ever heard was true? 
\n\n
Children\'s stories. Nightmares. Mythologies. Religions. Can they all be real?
\n\n
A certain branch of science believes that if the human mind can imagine something, it must have at one time existed. 
\n\n
Skeptics will deny it as the fanciful ravings of the mad. The true believers will deny it, too, because they know that the truth is far, far uglier. It is much worse than the simple tales of good vs. evil. 
\n\n
Only now are we discovering the infinite number of parallel universes existing alongside ours, all the time branching off in countless other directions. Every story we have ever heard is true somewhere. This is the story of one of those universes, where man\'s very existence is hanging on by a thread. 
\n\n
Monsters are real. Armies of them, lead by Gods, all with the same goal: return home. Blackened, twisted hearts, looking for the only vengeance that will bring them peace. Destroy all competitors. Follow their God into the heart of battle, emerge victorious, and march back to the hell that spawned them. Return. Home. 
\n\n
The struggle to stay alive will be a daily battle. The weak will sooner forget these days. Gods and Monsters, Demons and Undead, and the tools of war, are the only reality. This is all too real… this is Tower Defense Wars!
\n\n</string>

    <!-- ICE -->
    <string name="almanac_race_ice">She is made of ice, they say, the Goddess of Winter, Skaði, aggrieved wife of Njörðr, leader of the frozen armies of Norse warriors. At one time, she sought vengeance, but now she seeks only home. Her father, Þjazi, was killed seeking out the shape-shifting Loki. In a fit of righteous anger, she came to the gods, sword in hand. But they placated her. They soothed her anger. They gave her power. There is an empty void inside Skaði that grows daily with the wrongs committed on her house. It is a blackness chasing light. Of the nine worlds in Norse mythology, only Niflhel, a hellish, frozen wasteland, can contain this blackness from swallowing Creation. There her army marches. </string>
    <string name="almanac_frozen_soldier">Trapped in a frozen prison for centuries, the Ice Vikings were brought back to life when Skaði came under attack. She needed to summon an army, and turned to the mass graves of the followers of her deceased father, Þjazi. The Ice Vikings have been warned that their freedom is temporary: win, and claim a favored place in Nifhel. Lose, and remain frozen and fighting forever.</string>
    <string name="almanac_frozen_soldier_horseman">Like the frozen soldiers forever marching on foot, Frozen Horsemen are cooly calculating. Differing from the famously fleet-footed Elvish, Skaði\'s equine army moves slowly and methodically. Though technically capable of a spirited gallop, a Frozen Horseman is more likely to exhaust his enemy than chase him. Knowing that no corner of the earth is too cold, too dark, or too inhospitable, he will simply follow his prey. He will never stop. He will never rest. Not until his enemies have relinquished their final dying gasps.</string>
    <string name="almanac_polar_bear">These fierce animals are not known for their intelligence, insight, or adaptability. They are known for vicious strength. With powerful, meaty paws and razor sharp nails, many a solider has met their fate being plucked from the ground only to encounter their insatiable teeth. These knives lay in wait inside a jaw that crushes frozen granite as easily as flesh, making escape exceedingly rare.  </string>
    <string name="almanac_ice_golem">Made of an ice more dense than anything found on the modern Earth, the Ice Golem\'s fist is as hard as frozen rock. It\'s soul, if it ever had one, has long since iced over, and it lives only to serve Skaði\'s cruel bidding. There are two options on encountering an Ice Golem: fight to the death, or run. And if one chooses to run, one better run fast.  </string>
    <string name="almanac_drake">Able to attack from frighteningly far distances, the Drake literally breaths an icy floe of hail, reigning terror on weaker, less mobile creatures. Earthly hailstorms have been known to destroy forests, decimate whole packs of wild animals, and even dent steel. Imagine what the Drake is capable of.  </string>
    <string name="almanac_water_cannon">This powerful cannon harnesses one of Earth\'s most basic elements, water, and turns it into the knife edge of an endlessly renewable weapon.</string>
    <string name="almanac_water_catapult">Water is both infinitely formable and surprisingly heavy. Both facts are exploited by the deadly Water Catapault.</string>
    <string name="almanac_water_pillar">Moving slowly, almost methodically, a vast enough quantity of water can swell high, surround the lowlands, and eventually suffocate anything in its path.</string>
    <string name="almanac_water_emitter">Strange that something known to give life can so adroitly function as a machine of death, but such is the Water Emitter. Like the torture known to some cultures, the Water Emitter slowly but surely suffocates its opponents with a simple stream of water. </string>

    <!-- WIND -->
    <string name="almanac_race_wind">Before there was rain, before there snow, there was wind, drifting along the land, covering the Earth in a blanket of change. There is one who controls the wind, and in so doing, controls the movement of the sands, the seeds, and the seasons. His name is Quetzalcoatl. The winged serpent is more than a God: he is an ally, a friend, a tormenter, and a marker of place. Quetzalcoatl is the gap between Earth and Sky. He is one of the few that can travel to Xibalba, the Maya underworld, and return without the scent of death about him. Xibalba is a place of fear; what business Quetzalcoatl has there is hard to say. But he\'s raised an army to follow him. He\'s awakened the wind.</string>
    <string name="almanac_human_archer">Long before the gun, there was the archer, perhaps the most feared combatant of the Medieval Age. Now toiling for Quetzacoatl, who has promised them the backing of a furious wind, these agile fighters are able to attack at long range. Using an arrowhead wrapped in a rusted barb of tiny steel hooks, anyone lucky enough to survive an encounter with a group of archers, of which there are few known to history, will emerge scarred for the rest of their days.</string>
    <string name="almanac_human_archer_horseman">If the Archer has a weakness, and many will argue that it does not, it is that their need to set and aim leaves them relatively exposed. Enter the Mounted Archer, trained to control a wild beast will still maintaining deadly accuracy. An encounter with a group of Mounted Archers will leave the sky blackened, thousands of arrows, each an emissary of a death foretold, raining down from above. </string>
    <string name="almanac_panda_bear">Though often adored for their comely looks, the Giant Panda is a fiercely territorial beast, with thick mandibles and knife-like claws. While adapted to a fairly sedentary life, the Giant Pandas are irritable and extremely defensive of their own kind. Knowing this, Quetzalcoatl prods the Giant Pandas to no end, separating mother from cub, and isolating the ursine warriors from their native homeland. He has angered them, and while misplaced, their anger will be quenched in blood.</string>
    <string name="almanac_lightning_golem">The ancient Mayans worshipped Chaac, a rain serpent said to control the lightning in the skies, often placing him above the winged serpent Quetzalcoatl. Quetzalcoatl, knowing full well of Chaac\'s power, scoured the heavens and hells in search of the Lightning Golem. Having found him, and having secured his allegiance, the Lightning Golem will serve Quetzalcoatl like the rain serves the clouds: unflinchingly, creating death like the cloud creates a puddle. </string>
    <string name="almanac_dragon">Perhaps no single creature has benefited as much from their new master as the Dragon. Already a beast known throughout the ages, under Quetzalcoatl, the Dragon is even more fearsome, having learned every nuisance of the churning wind from its winged liege. The dragon is a fiery serpent of alarming ability. </string>
    <string name="almanac_lightning_cannon">Since the dawn of mankind, lesser creatures have hoped to control the Heavens, and with it, the power of Zeus\' lightning bolts. Now they can.</string>
    <string name="almanac_griffin_statue">Though majestic in its form, and regal in its countenance, look no further than its talons to understand the true nature of the Griffin.</string>
    <string name="almanac_lightning_pillar">A column of incredible natural energy, this pillar is both a magnet for power, and a capable projector of matchless destruction.</string>
    <string name="almanac_lightning_emitter">Able to function in short burts of extreme acuity, the Lightning Emitter is a shocking force to behold from far away; any closer, of course, is not a show, but a death sentence.</string>

    <!-- EARTH -->
    <string name="almanac_race_earth">Man created religion to describe God. God created Man to reflect his image. But Gaia, Mother Gaia, created the Gods. Gaia, creator of the Earth, is the font from which the river of life flows. She is the spirit and the harmony of existence. The Greeks looked to Gaia for guidance above all others. She shined upon them. And they turned on her, drunk on the wine they made from the grapes she provided, drunk on the power over a life she but merely allowed. So, she will lead them to Tartarus. She will show them what pain is. Tartarus, the abyss, the dark hole in the center of being, the underworld of the damned. Tartarus, a resting place and the name of the God who rests there. Tartarus will be their fate; Gaia will lead her army to their destiny, and then she will wash her hands of the filthy, unrepentant failure. </string>
    <string name="almanac_elvish_archer">For elves, being an archer is not a job, it is a way of life. Learning the long bow from the time they learn to walk, an elf develops a keen sixth sense for archery, as though these tools of war were an extension of his very being. Though not always the largest and strongest race, elves use their superior vision, cunning, and bow skill to easily defeat lessor opponents, calling upon Gaia, the Earth goddess, in times of great need. Cross them at your own risk. </string>
    <string name="almanac_elvish_archer_horseman">Few architects of war, be they man or machine, can strike as quickly and decisively as the Elvish Archer Horseman. Renowned for the almost spiritual connection between rider and steed, the Elves who master both the bow and the beast are honored in the Elvish culture, and uniformly feared outside of it. This is with good reason. Using a short bow that allows for a full range of motion, these mobile assassins scan the horizon, select their targets, and strike with alarming alacrity.</string>
    <string name="almanac_grizzly_bear">A naturally evolved killer, and the undisputed king of its forested homeland, the Grizzly walks slowly because he can. Yet at full sprint, the bear is faster than all but the fleetest of animals, and strong enough to rip bones from their sockets. If its sharpened teeth and claws don\'t kill its prey, it will occasionally destroy opponents with blunt, brute force and hammer fisted paws. </string>
    <string name="almanac_earth_golem">Rising from the Earth\'s crust, the Earth Golem is a complex beast, a collection of micro-organisms, gases, and stone, held together with swamp mud and a singular focus: return to the Earth from which it came. It does not fight its opponents so much as swallow them and become one with them, evaporating any trace of what had previously stood before it like mud flowing into a passing stream. </string>
    <string name="almanac_eagle">In modern times a symbol of freedom and justice, the ancient Eagle is a gigantic bird of prey, attacking with speed and surprising force. Its talons tear through flesh, leaving puncture wounds that cause a slow and painful death. At best, the Eagle will lift its opponent and deposit them for a long fall and a much quicker and more certain demise. Make no mistake: this is a cursed bird born of damned soul.</string>
    <string name="almanac_rock_cannon">No substance known is as plentiful as the constant, crushing power of rock, and no cannon is as relentless. </string>
    <string name="almanac_stone_catapult">A rain of stones sounds like a Biblical plague, but the Stone Catapault is able to produce such a fury at a moment\'s notice.</string>
    <string name="almanac_earth_pillar">Little known in some circles, but the Earth is composed of far more than mere dirt, rock, and water. There is an internal energy, a life-force, that binds these elements together. Whether harnessed for good or for evil, this ineffable energy has a  power that\'s undeniable. </string>
    <string name="almanac_dirt_emitter">Neither technologically advanced, nor magically unique, the Dirt Emitter is a simple, brutal creation. However, its danger is not to be discounted. Simply ask anyone who has ever been buried alive. That is, if you can find a survivor. </string>

    <!-- FIRE -->
    <string name="almanac_race_fire">The Hindu religion has many Gods, Indra and Soma, Vishnu and Rudra. And then there is Agni, God of fire and acceptor of sacrifices. Agni is the messenger, the conduit between heaven and earth, the link between the humans and the deities. Agni is angry. The Gods showed humans the path to wisdom, but they have forsaken it. They will have to be taught again. They will have to follow the path. Agni will lead them to Naraka, the Hindu underworld. Naraka is a place of torment, an eternal land of suffering feared by the Buddhists and the Jainists alike. Agni makes no distinctions. He will rest his hand on the shoulder of the damned, and blaze a trail through the heart of any aggressor. Agni is immortal. His army is undead. Together, they will return the world to its natural state: suffering. </string>
    <string name="almanac_mummy">Like a man stumbling from a burning building, the Mummy is slow and disoriented. But it does not seek an escape toward life. Rather it hopes to drag others into its undead world of misery. The Mummy is not strong, it is not fast, and it is not smart. But more than any creature known, it will not stop fighting. It will never stop fighting: tormented, broken, and bruised.  </string>
    <string name="almanac_mummy_horseman">The Undead Rider possesses the same manic resolve as the Mummy, but solves the Mummy\'s biggest weakness: its slow movement. Able to strike at a moment\'s notice, the Undead Rider is the perfect combination of sheer speed, nimble dexterity, and a brutal desire to crush the will of its opponents both near and far. </string>
    <string name="almanac_fiery_bear">Resembling the common black bear in build, Agni has scoured Naraka, the fiery underworld, for an undead assailant similar in size, speed, and strength. Unable to find an appropriate match, he created the Burning Bears, forged in an animal sacrifice of innocent creatures and damned human spirits. A Burning Bear is intelligent enough to stalk its prey, indefatigable, and completely impervious to even the most intense forms of heat. Further, Agni has imbued each with a fiery rage and a unhinged disposition. The Burning Bears are unpredictable, intractable, and reliably deadly.</string>
    <string name="almanac_fire_golem">The right application of time and pressure will create a diamond. The wrong application will create a Hell Spawn, a lethal mixture of molten lava and crushed Earth. Whether scalding its opponents with its boiling hot fists, or pulverizing then with its ceaseless, methodical movements, the Hell Spawn\'s only goal is to inflict its misery upon the world, accepting all sacrifices upon the altar of its own malcontent.</string>
    <string name="almanac_falcon">There is no single animal as synonymous with speed as the Falcon, and consequently, no animal capable of striking so quickly and efficiently. Diving towards its prey from lofty altitudes, the Falcon has often struck the death blow before its opponent even saw it coming, wedging its hardened beak into the skull of the interloper. Agni smiles each time the Falcon strikes its unwitting prey. </string>
    <string name="almanac_flame_cannon">Heat attacks the very nature of a creature\'s cells, and few, if any, can stand up to the raging infermo of the Flame Cannon.</string>
    <string name="almanac_flame_catapult">The only thing that fire lacks is the ability to surprise. It is too bright and too hot to catch many off guard. At least until the Flame Catapault enters the battle.</string>
    <string name="almanac_fire_pillar">Surrounding a fire pillar is a dance with sure death, beautiful in its own nimble way, the fire bending to the shape of the winds, before engulfing its prey in a cauldron of heat. </string>
    <string name="almanac_fire_emitter">Like the blacksmith\'s furnaces used to forge the cold steel that conquered medieval Europe, the Fire Emitter radiates an intense heat immobilizing all but the most-stout hearted to come near it.</string>

    <!-- LIFE -->
    <string name="almanac_race_life">To be cannonised, to become a Saint, one most devote their life to the cause of the Christians, and to the salvation of their fellow man. Some seek salvation through the Book, others through the sword. Hugues de Payens, founder and Grand Master of the Knights Templar, was a warrior saint, a Crusader, and military leader of true grit and uncommon genius. De Payens, like all of the Grand Masters that followed him, accepted the position for life, sworn to defend the Cross. Only in death could one finally rest. In his life, de Payens killed many a soul for the greater good. For his crimes, he must wait in Gehenna, an ancient repository for the wicked. Once there, he may find his fate is not to wait Purgatory. Or he may suffer for eternity. It is not his lot to know. He knows only that there the answer awaits him, as it awaits his zealous followers. </string>
    <string name="almanac_zealot">A Zealot is blind to any truth that does not conform to his view. Like a living machine, his scope is narrowed. The Knights have forged these warriors of faith through deception, and they fight not with anger or envy, but with an emotional depth far exceeding that of the trivial world. Their fervor is impossible to attain by mortals, and with this zealous focus, foes soon realize that a true Zealot will stop at nothing, often defeating opponents many times their size and strength.</string>
    <string name="almanac_zealot_horseman">Once a noble paragon of virtue and chivalry, the knight was also a highly skilled killer, combining swordsmanship and horsemanship into one deadly combatant. Previously, a knight\'s strict adherence to a moral code kept him from fighting for evil. But now, with this code long lost, these Mercenaries have begun to fight for the highest bidder, seeking to return to Gehenna and torture their enemies mercilessly for eternity.  </string>
    <string name="almanac_seraphim">The Seraphim are tirelessly active, their devotion to prayer bordering on insanity. Often, they are thought of as burning, so fiery is their need for religious resolution. In Hugues de Payens, they have found a leader uniquely suited to putting their industry to good use, sending them on an endless series of death-bound missions, always promising that soon he will provide them with the calm they so desperately seek. </string>
    <string name="almanac_life_golem">Folklore holds that the Rabbi Judah Loew ben Bezalel created the first Golem to defend the Jews of Prague against the ghetto pogroms. Realizing that he had created a monster that could not be controlled, Rabbi Loew was forced to put down the Golem before its increasingly violent outburst threatened the further death of gentile innocents. Such power, and such wanton destruction of his people, was not lost on Hugues de Payens. He resurrected the Jewish Golem for his Knights Templar, creating the Golem Crusader: dim witted, immoral, and  virtually unstoppable.</string>
    <string name="almanac_angel">Wide-winged and imbued with a power some consider stronger than any other, Divine Right, Angels possess superhuman strength and a narrow focus: they will not hesitate to dispose of those that stand in the way of a reunification with their true God. Of course, who is “standing in the way” is up to their own interpretation, and many an innocent as fallen at the hands of these winged warriors.</string>
    <string name="almanac_energy_cannon">The Energy Cannon fires rounds of pure energy, even more elemental than electricity, reducing anything living or dead into a mass of inanimate material waste. </string>
    <string name="almanac_angel_statue">Behold the power of the Angel: a symbol strength, solemnity, and obedience.</string>
    <string name="almanac_life_pillar">There are creatures on Earth able to thrive in caldronous heat. There are cells that need light and those that crave darkness There are plants that breath in the gases other animals exhale.  Such is the Life Pillar, a wellspring of Life energy used to bring about death. </string>
    <string name="almanac_holy_water_emitter">Like so many weapons of war, the truly Holy have nothing to fear from the Holy Water Emitter. Like so many wars, this one will not be faught by the Holy.  </string>

    <!-- DEATH -->
    <string name="almanac_race_death">In Haitian Voodou, the veve is a ritual symbol used to represent the powerful spirits, known as Loa. The most important Loa, Damballa, the Sky God and creator of all life, is represented by two serpents. Like a snake, Damballa cannot talk. He expresses himself by speaking through flame. Bondyè, the unknowable creator of all, cannot be spoken to. He expresses himself through Damballa. But much as Damalla\'s ways are a mystery to man, Bondyè\'s ways are a mystery to Damballa.  When his follower\'s offerings do not suit him, Damballa burns whole villages. When Damballa does not suit Bondyè, there is no telling the consequences. Should this unknowable creature decide to bring Hell to Earth, no force in the universe will be able to stop him. The dead will rise and do his bidding. Mystery will be replaced by blinding truth.   </string>
    <string name="almanac_zombie">The Zombie, already dead, lives without happiness or fear. His is a life of purpose. Eternal existence, sought by everyone from Ponce de Leon in the West, to the Brahmins of the East, is the curse of the Zombie, forever wandering in a ceaseless cycle of insufferable pain. He is Damballa\'s puppet, content only in the Hell on Earth that has come to be his home. </string>
    <string name="almanac_zombie_horseman">Like a headless horseman unleashed upon the night, the Zombie Rider moves tirelessly over the cracked soil of a scorched Earth. Inside him there are no thoughts, no dreams. There is not even a call for vengeance. His life is far more simple. Like a plant reaches toward the sun, the Zombie Rider roams the planet, willed to destroy everything in his path such that he may one day be restored. </string>
    <string name="almanac_succubus">Unlike so many of the vile creatures brought to war here, the Succubus can appear as though a delicate beauty. By the time her nubile form has blackened in the eyes of her beholder, it is too late. They will see her true form for a moment, the reptilian skin of a soulless instrument whose pleasure arises in pain, and then they will be eliminated. </string>
    <string name="almanac_undead_golem">A composition of all that is ugly in the world, all that is tormented and blistered, the Undead Golem combines the most useless, most toxic, most downtrodden, and most reviled waste into one reanimated being. Like a living Voodoo doll, Damballa has taken disparate parts and formed them into the Undead Golem. Barely sentient, but profoundly destructive, the Undead Golem betrays only the merest vestige of control to its creator. Beyond that, it is a machine, brought into life to kill, and only to kill.</string>
    <string name="almanac_fallen_angel">Fallen Angels once lived cradled in a blanket of boundless love and eternal tranquility. And they rejected it, consumed with a desire for power. Long since cast out of the Kingdom of Heaven, Fallen Angels will exact swift justice on any creature preventing their ascension to the Throne of a doomed Earth – especially those foolish enough to compare them to the God which they take as their sworn enemy.  </string>
    <string name="almanac_poison_cannon">The Poison Cannon spews its noxious effluvia out into the world, an endless smokestack of harmful gases and waste oils, that few can withstand. The air burns black while the Poison Cannon works. </string>
    <string name="almanac_gargoyle_statue">Watchful and ready, a Gargoyal remains perched, always hanging on the edge of flight and fight.</string>
    <string name="almanac_undead_pillar">There is something inside the heart of the undead, or inside what remains of their soul, that keeps them upright and moving, yet not alive. Whatever this force is, it is powerfully transformative, and likely to poison whatever living creatures come into contact with it.</string>
    <string name="almanac_toxic_gas_emitter">There are some substances so antithetical to life that their toxicity crosses all manner of creature and all worlds of origin. The Toxic Gas Emitter releases such substances on the enemy.</string>

    <!-- COMBO TOWERS -->
    <string name="almanac_flame_whip">A fiery tendril emerges from the Flame Whip like a burning lasso, stinging opponents with a lash of flame, or encircling them in ring of fire.</string>
    <string name="almanac_water_whip">The Water Whip exists somewhere between liquid and solid. Though fluid in movement, those struck by its snapping, violent strike will surely by left with a scarring memory of its solid state. Further proof that the surface of liquid water is like steel given the right circumstances. </string>
    <string name="almanac_tentical_whip">Like a giant octopus, or a fully realized version of the mythological Kraken, the Tentical Whip possesses one thick, muscular rope of a tentical, able to strike its prey why surprising accuracy and unparalled speed.</string>
    <string name="almanac_flame_crystallizer">A flame is simply a visible cue that there is fire. It is a trick of the light, a ghost removed from the essense. The Flame Crystallizer harnesses fire\'s heat, it conjures it from thin air, with no flame required.</string>
    <string name="almanac_ice_crystallizer">Earth\'s air is a mixture of many things, but even in the harshest desert, there is a trace of moisture. The Ice Crystallizer takes hold of this moisture and creates instant ice. This may not sound feasome until one pictures ice forming from the inside out, veins, arteries, and organs not excluded. </string>
    <string name="almanac_earth_crystallizer">From the shining lights of Heaven, to the darkest corners of Hell, there is a magic in the very concept of solid ground, of existence. Where does it come from? How does this material come into being? The Earth Crystallizer provides no answers, but it is surely quite an object.</string>
    <string name="almanac_lightning_blade">Lightning cuts through the sky, cleaving the night into two halves, seperated by a white hot band of destructive electricity. The Lightning Blade takes that electricity and contains its power in the blade of a sword. Contains its power, but for how long?</string>
    <string name="almanac_ice_blade">A cut rips through flesh with a bolt of hot pain, tearing muscle close to bone. A blade made of ice will not lessen that pain. Its cooled core will not prevent the scars of war. The Ice Blade is the worst of two worlds colliding, and its foe best take notice. </string>
    <string name="almanac_flame_blade">The Flame Blade battles in the same heat under which it once emerged from the forge. Glowing hot, with an searing edge able to melt even the strongest of armor, the Flame Blade\'s effectiveness is limited only when dealing with creatures with the utmost resistence to burning.</string>
    <string name="almanac_earth_ballista">A timeless weapon, the ballista has been repurposed by Gaia for the sieges yet to come. With missiles especially designed to withstand the strongest of combatants, the Earth Ballista is built using the technology of the ancient Greeks and Romans, but the materials of a God. </string>
    <string name="almanac_ice_ballista">The Ice Ballista takes slow, inert ice and propels it to tremendous speeds. Coupled with precisely engineered stays and springs, the bolts fired by the Ice Ballista are defended by few.</string>
    <string name="almanac_flame_ballista">Many an ancient city fell to an onslaught by the ballista corps. Agni has called upon this famed weapon because it is so easily bolstered with the addition of fire. The Flame Ballista combines pounding force with the destructiveness of flame in a weapon for the ages.</string>

    <!-- COMBO CREATURES -->
    <string name="almanac_elf_wizard">The noble Wizards have long wrestled to bring the World into harmony, using their wisdom (and a healthy dash of magic) to suppress the creatures that would do their brethren harm. While generally peaceable and unlikely to start confrontations, Wizards are known for their bitterness, some holding grudges that have lasted for generations of men. Built frail and slight, a Wizard is like a clever rouse, a Trojan horse in the shape of a man. Though unable to wrestle even a small child to the ground, a strong Wizard could force an entire city onto its knees in the blink of an eye.</string>
    <string name="almanac_human_mage">One of the most powerful magic users known to man or beast, Mages control the spells of which mortal men can only dream. Unlike Wizards, who are bound to an oath and a code, Mages use their powers freely, selling their services to the highest bidders or striking out on their own to plunder riches and grasp for control of a world turned against them. Mages are bilious and twisted, but should not be discounted: they are extremely dangerous users of the dark arts and have long ago forgotten the meaning of the word fear.</string>
    <string name="almanac_human_necromancer">Providing the most direct link between the land of the living and the land of the dead, Necromancers are as skilled as they are tortured, imprisoned with the very knowledge they have spent their lives honing. Unable to fully inhabit either world, Necromancers exist in a desperate schism, conjuring spells and creatures in a hopeless attempt to fight off both the demons they face without, and the demons they face within. The living love. The dead rest. But the necromancer does neither, slowly syphoning off the last pained breaths of a twisted mortal coil. </string>
    <string name="almanac_troll">Nature is a wonderful artist, shaping its creatures to reflect both their place in the world and their likely means of interacting with it. This being true, the Troll\'s wretched, sunken face, pockmarked skin, and crooked spines reflects their station: gatekeepers and bottom-dwellers, shiftless, craven, and without remorse. The well-bred Troll will learn not only how to eek out its living on the backs of others, but will develop an uncanny sense of the moment, seizing power when the balances tip ever so slightly. Disgusting to behold, olfactious, and shifty, they will use any available means to gain what they want, even preying on other\'s revulsion as to the their very existence.</string>
    <string name="almanac_dwarf">There are few who are as aware of their bodies, as in tune with its use as a weapon that has both strengths and weaknesses, as the pugnacious Dwarf clans. Dwarves are squatly built, and though powerful for their size, are not as strong as the animals and adversaries they routinely dispatch. Experts in close combat, and unafraid to reduce the battle to its lowest common denominator, a Dwarf is unlikely to retreat when it knows that tireless industry will likely produce a kill. Able to withstand great changes in both heat and cold, resilient, and possessed of great stamina, the man who takes the Dwarves\' small stature lightly might not be a man, at least a living one, for long. </string>
    <string name="almanac_halfling">Related to the ancient humans, Halfings have evolved as a crafty race of thieves, charlatans, and deceptively skilled combatants. Though limited in strength, and not known for their outright speed, Halflings are quick, cunning, and vicious, using their tiny stature to hide in the shadows before striking with lethal agility. Halflings can be easily overpowered in a fair fight. Consequently, Halflings rarely fight fair. </string>
    <string name="almanac_kobold">A forgotten branch of the evolutionary ladder, the Kobold is part human and part lizard, yet keeps no allegiance with either species. Kobolds are known to build traps, ambushes, and other small machines of war in order to leverage their superior intellect against creatures of greater size and strength. Rarely seen, Kobolds are thought to be invisible by many. While this may be true, their knotted muscles, short stabbing blades, and evilly complex creations attest to their existence.</string>
    <string name="almanac_gnome">Perhaps the smallest of all creatures, far less is known about Gnomes than other earthly dwellers. Unlike magic users and the undead, the Gnomes do not inhabit foreign worlds or hide in the present using tricks and spells. They are expert cave dwellers, rangers, and surprisingly good swimmers. They live on mountainsides and in treetops. Their engineering skills and the creation of their tiny, perfect machines is the stuff of legend. They are the ultimate survivors. Gnomes are rarely seen, and create no aura of danger around their movements. But do not cross them unless you have answers: how do you strike a foe that can\'t be found? How do you fight an enemy that\'s won before the battle\'s even begun?</string>
    <string name="almanac_ghoul">One of the most fiendish creatures of the night, Ghouls are the last vestige of an earthly soul turning over to the Land of the Dead. Like the memory of a nightmare, a Ghoul is present and real, able to strike paralyzing fear into the hearts of man. And yet, in a moment, this memory drifts, carried to another place and time like sand in a wind storm. A Ghoul is not bound by the same sense of seconds, minutes, and years that affects most that would do harm: it is an idea that exists beyond such trivial concerns, tangential to the arc of time, a death knell that rings but doesn\'t echo. </string>
    <string name="almanac_human_witch">In a world of magical creatures, Witches occupy a lowly station, long ago selling off a portion of their worldly souls in return for a modicum of supernatural power. Though not as gifted as other creatures, neither especially strong physically or magically, witches have little to lose, and are compelled to fight through a powerful attraction: it is the odd witch that does not have her fixation, and once attached, she is virtually unable to think of anything else. Be wary of witches, as only death can dislodge them from their singular missions.</string>
    <string name="almanac_female_necromancer">Providing the most direct link between the land of the living and the land of the dead, Necromancers are as skilled as they are tortured, imprisoned with the very knowledge they have spent their lives honing. Unable to fully inhabit either world, Necromancers exist in a desperate schism, conjuring spells and creatures in a hopeless attempt to fight off both the demons they face without, and the demons they face within. The living love. The dead rest. But the necromancer does neither, slowly syphoning off the last pained breaths of a twisted mortal coil. </string>
    <string name="almanac_female_elf_mage">One of the most powerful magic users known to man or beast, Mages control the spells of which mortal men can only dream. Unlike Wizards, who are bound to an oath and a code, Mages use their powers freely, selling their services to the highest bidders or striking out on their own to plunder riches and grasp for control of a world turned against them. Mages are bilious and twisted, but should not be discounted: they are extremely dangerous users of the dark arts and have long ago forgotten the meaning of the word fear.</string>

</resources>